https://www.americares.org/our-privacy-policy/

videos
Trust Americares to spend your donation wisely. Rated 4/4 stars by Charity Navigator.
Privacy Policy
Americares Foundation, Inc. has established this privacy policy to demonstrate our commitment to maintaining the confidentiality and privacy of information about visitors to our web sites and donors.
This policy explains why we collect particular information and how we will protect your personal privacy both offline and within our web sites. The following also discloses our information gathering and dissemination practices for the web sites located at:
americares.orgsecure.americares.orgamericaresindia.orgamericares.org/elsalvadormedicaloutreach.americares.org americaresfreeclinics.orgsafetynetcenter.orgThese are collectively referred to below as “the Site.”
In order to fully understand your rights we encourage you to read this Privacy Policy. Our privacy policies may be changed from time to time, simply by posting such changes on our site, so we encourage you to check back regularly. Any such change will be effective immediately upon posting.
This Privacy Policy notifies you of:
What personally identifiable information of yours is collected through the Site Who collects such information How such information is used With whom your information may be shared What choices you have regarding collection, use and distribution of your informationWhat are cookies and how they are used on the Site What kind of security procedures are in place to protect against the loss, misuse or alteration of information under our control How you can correct any inaccuracies in your information or “Opt-Out”
What Information We Collect and How We Use That Information:
We do not collect personally identifiable information from individuals unless they provide it to us voluntarily. This means we do not require you to provide information to us in order to view our web sites. Americares only collects personal information that is voluntarily and knowingly provided to us by a site visitor wanting to make a donation, sign up for our mailing list, apply for employment or volunteer to work with Americares, or any party making a donation via mail, phone, in-person, or event attendance — information that we need to respond appropriately to them. Our registration and contribution forms generally require users to give us their contact information that may include name, address, zip/postal codes, email address, format preference (HTML vs. Text), interests and similar information. This information is available to Americares and third-party service providers involved in the operation of this site, or any other Americares business. Whether you provide us with your information via the site or in an offline manner, we make a serious effort to require all third-party service providers to hold personal information in strict confidence. While we believe these companies are upstanding, reputable members of the community of providers offering services to non-profit organizations and will treat your personal information responsibly, we do not own or control them.
Internet Protocol (IP) Address: Information:
We collect an IP address from all visitors to our Site. An IP address is a number that is automatically assigned to your computer when you use the Internet; it tells us the domain name of each user to the Site, but not the actual email address. We use IP addresses to help us diagnose problems with our server, administer our Site, analyze trends, track users’ movement, gather broad demographic information for aggregate use in order for us to improve the site, and deliver customized, personalized content. IP addresses are not linked to personally identifiable information and are not shared with other organizations for commercial purposes at any time
Use of “Cookies”:
Our Site may use cookies to enhance your experience while using our Site. “Cookies” are small files that generally most Web sites transfer to your computer when you are browsing that Web site. They are not programs that harm a visitor’s system or files, and Americares does not use this technology to obtain personal information from its online visitors. The use of “cookies” helps us to recognize repeat visitors, analyze trends, and gather broad demographic information for aggregate use in order for us to improve the site.“Cookies” make your Web-surfing experience easier by performing certain usage and record-keeping functions such as saving your passwords or your personal preferences regarding your use of a Web site and to make sure that, for example, you don’t see the same ad repeatedly. Cookies are generally considered to be an industry standard.Your browser is probably set by default to accept cookies. However, if you would prefer not to receive cookies, you can alter the configuration of your browser to refuse cookies.
Setting Cookie Preferences
You may limit the cookies set in your browser or remove them entirely. Note that declining cookies may impact your ability to use our Site. At any point, you may elect to change your browser’s settings to delete cookies that have already been set and to reject new cookies. To learn more, visit the help pages of your browser.
Security:
All online transactions and all information provided to Americares are transmitted using SSL (Secure Socket Layer) encryption. SSL is a proven, industry standard coding system that lets your browser automatically encrypt or scramble data before you send it to us.  On all pages of our Site, including secure donation pages, the user will notice the website address at the top of the browser screen starts with an “https” instead of an “http”, and a closed lock symbol appears at the end of the address window – indicating that the pages are secure. We do not store sensitive information from our visitors or donors, such as credit cards or social security numbers. We also protect account information by placing it on a secure portion of the Site that is only accessible by certain qualified employees of Americares.
Protecting your information is of great importance to Americares and something we take very seriously. While our methods are the accepted industry standard for security protocol, and make it extremely difficult for your credit card data to be intercepted by anyone else, no data transmission over the Internet, is ever 100% secure. So while we strive to protect your information, we cannot ensure or warrant the security of such information. If you prefer to donate by mail, please send your check to Americares 88 Hamilton Ave. Stamford, Ct 06902, or to make a credit card donation over the phone, please call us at (800) 486-4357 or (203) 658-9500.
Opt In/Opt Out:
If you register on the Americares Web Site, or make an online or offline donation and supply us with your email and/or postal address you may receive periodic mailings or online communications from us with information about our current programs and activities around the world. If you do not wish to receive or would like to adjust the volume and types of communications you receive from Americares by postal mail or email, please contact us and let us know your preferences by emailing us at donorrelations@americares.org or call us at (800) 486-4357.  Once you have notified us of your preferences, it will take approximately 2-4 weeks to remove you from all emails and up to 6-8 weeks for removal from the mailing list. Please be patient with the process. Our goal is to provide you with only the information you wish to receive and in the manner you wish to receive it.
Americares does not rent, or sell your email or postal address; however we may from time to time share your name and postal address with other similar charitable non-profit organizations unless you opt-out. If you would prefer that your name not be shared with other organizations, please send us a request by email at donorrelations@americares.org or call us at (800) 486-4357.The only exceptions to Opting Out where Americares could disclose personal information would involve instances required by a law or a regulatory authority. Additionally information could be disclosed in rare cases if we have reason to believe that disclosure of this information is necessary to contact and/or bring legal action against a person(s) who may be inflicting injury or interfering with Americares rights, personnel, and property, Americares web site users or anyone who could be potentially harmed by such activities, whether intended or not.
Tell A Friend:
If a user elects to use our referral service for informing a friend about the Site, we ask them for the friend’s name and email address. Americares will automatically send the friend a one-time email inviting them to visit the Site. Americares stores this information for the sole purpose of sending this one-time email.
Children Under 13 Visiting Our Site:
Americares does not knowingly ask for information from children age 13 and under. Visitors who are 13 years of age or under should ask their parent or legal guardian for assistance in using the Site and should not submit any personally identifiable information to Americares.
Other Web Sites:
Our Site may contain links to other Web sites. Please note that when you click on one of these links, you are entering another web site for which Americares has no responsibility. This privacy policy applies solely to the Americares Site.  We encourage you to read the privacy statements on all such sites as their policies may be different than ours.
Contacting the Web Site:
If you have any questions about this Privacy Policy, the practices of the Site or your dealings with the Site, you may contact: AmericaresAttention: Web Team88 Hamilton AvenueStamford, CT 06902  You can also send an email to our web team.
If you have requests or questions about your personal data or data collection in general, please email info@americares.org
Health Makes Everything Possible
Our Impact with Your Giving Dollar
Generous donors make all our achievements possible. We are able to respond to more disasters, expand our health programs and save more lives because of the individuals, foundations and corporations that trust Americares to improve the lives of people in the United States and around the world.
More than 98% of our resources support health programs.
Americares efficiency with your charitable dollar is one reason that we’re trusted by donors and consistently receive high marks from charity evaluators.
